Madukoma Blessed C.

Backend Engineer

Profile

A software engineer with 3+ years experience tasked with demystifying the amazing world of performant and scalable systems by designing and building high-quaility backend services. I intend to use my skills to effectively take on the backend engineering position at your organization/company.

Experience

Freelance Backend Engineer

September 2021 to Present

As a freelance backend engineer, I build backend services and APIs for customers, businesses and clients who either need the APIs or have existing frontend developers.

Backend Engineer (Contract) - StudyItLive

October 2021 to Present

At StudyItLive, I:

- · collaborated with other backend engineers to build the APIs in Python.
- executed core functionalities such as the authentication of users dashboard.
- · implemented the API documentation using Swagger.
- · executed requests to test the API endpoints.

Backend Engineer (Contract) - LockBook Limited

December 2021 to March 2022

At LockBook Limited, I:

- · developed and maintained the backend services written in Go.
- · set up and managed deployed servers.
- implemented core functionalities such as the creation of the license endpoint which generates licenses for the Purchase API.

Backend Engineer - PalmTree Technologies Limited

January 2021 to November 2021

- Collaborated with other PHP/Laravel developers to implement core features for the company's major software: <u>biz301.com</u> such as the creation of business shops for merchants, auto-generation of invoices for businesses on the platform and many more.
- Implemented a bill payment feature using Paystack's API.
- · Integrated CoralPay's billing system for payment of utility bills such as water and data.

Projects

Web-Based Accountability Register For Budget Management API (Contract) - Github

Developed an API for budget tracking using Golang and Postgres database by implementing features such as creation of a budget, addition of income and expenses based on validated user's input.

Light Automation Management System (LAMS) - Github / Live

My University's final year project, LAMS, developed using VueJS and Firebase is a web application that allows authenticated users to control their auto-registered lights by performing actions such as switching off the lights, and auto-calculation of energy used by each registered light.

Boxpaddy

As part of the core backend team for Revamp Technologies, I implemented the SMS and Email API services.

My Portfolio Website - Github / Live

Designed and developed my portfolio website using HTML, CSS and JavaScript.

Manga Scraper - Github

Developed a manga scraper in Go to download manga from websites and store as images.

Contact Me

blessedmadukoma@gmail.com

Ogun, Nigeria I'm willing to Relocate

+2349030609267, +2349156076286

Portfolio Links

Website Email

Twitter LinkedIn

Github Hashnode

Languages: Frameworks

· Go (Golang)

· Python: Flask

· SQL: PostgreSQL, MySQL

HTML

· css

JavaScript

Tools

VScode

Github

Git

BitBucket

TrelloHeroku

JiraSlack

OPEN SOURCE

Roadmap.sh

aided the Postgres section by including useful resources to serve as a guide.

EDUCATION

BSc, Software Engineering

Babcock University

2018 to 2022

Finished with a **First Class** with a CGPA of **4.55/5** while learning relevant course works such as Web Design and Development, Internet Technologies and much more.

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Executive President

Babcock University Computer Club

2021 to 2022

As the President of the Computing Association at Babcock, I:

- led the Executives and represented the team in all fora.
- organized events such as Seminar, Software Exhibition, and Debate by inviting prominent persons in the Tech Ecosystem to give talks and keynote speeches.
- liased with companies to provide SIWES placements for 300L BUCC students